Colton Grainger 1127 Hammock St Houston, TX 77009

June 4, 2017

#### Dear Sir or Madam:

I aim to gain employment as a Patient Coordinator starting July 24, 2017.

I have performed clerical work since 2015, when I was hired as a grading assistant. I found that, by taking a share of my supervisor's administrative responsibilities, I gave her more time to focus on research and curriculum design.

In 2016 I graduated with a B.S. in Mathematics-Physics. Shortly after, I committed to a year of service in the Episcopal Service Corps. I am fulfilling this commitment by working as a clerk at the YMCA International Services, a refugee resettlement agency in Houston, TX.

At the YMCA, I work on small team to support refugees with complex medical conditions. I balance clerical duties with direct case management. I directly serve 40 clients monthly—arranging medical appointments, transportation and interpretation. As a clerk, I maintain 240 client case files—medical records, financial eligibility information, and immigration documents—for 7 staff across 2 departments of the resettlement agency.

In contributing to an efficient workflow at your multi-provider chiropractic office, I anticipate that I will

- receive clients, schedule appointments and handle referrals;
- draft, revise, and copy-edit documents as needed;
- maintain physical/electronic records and sort sensitive mail;
- develop macros to manage client data and automate repetitive tasks; and
- relieve staff of miscellaneous administrative burdens.

As these responsibilities mirror those I have already taken on, I am confident that I can increase your office's administrative capacity from my start date.

Outside of my professional interests, I am passionate about cycling, hiking, and computer science. I have ambition to pursue graduate studies in Mathematics and, eventually, publish research in support of environmental preservation.

Respectfully,

# Colton Grainger

P.S. I am available via email, by phone after 3:00 P.M. PST, or by scheduled video-chat.

208-585-7373

coltoncgrainger@gmail.com ⋈

coltongrainger.github.io 🖘

**OBJECTIVE** 

To gain employment as a Patient Coordinator, with start date July 24, 2017.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

- 1 year of service in refugee medical care.
- 2 years' expertise in clerical work and data management.
- Ability to balance competing administrative tasks.

**EDUCATION** 

# **B.S.** in Mathematics-Physics

May 2016

The College of Idaho, Caldwell, ID

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Clerk — Refugee Medical Care

September 2016 - July 2017

YMCA International Services, Houston, TX

- Supported 7 staff over 240 client cases (60 medical, 180 social adjustment).
- Scheduled medical appointments with transportation and interpretation.
- Coordinated billing during policy changes to Refugee Medical Assistance.
- Vetted client data for the implementation of 3 SQL databases.

# **Grading Assistant**

September 2015 – December 2015

The College of Idaho

- Corrected weekly assignments for 25 general physics students.
- Corresponded with faculty to ensure objective and accurate grading.

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

### **Service Corps Fellow**

August 2016 – July 2017

Texas Episcopal Service Corps, Houston, TX

- Completed a year of service (1,800 hours) while living in community.
- Participated in professional development and communication training.

#### Lead Counselor — Gem Boys State

June 2014 and 2015

Northwest Nazerene University, Nampa, ID

- Hosted a summer camp on state government with the American Legion.
- Supervised 100 students and 12 junior counselors on a team of 4 staff.

JOB RELATED COMPETENCIES

### Technology

- Microsoft Office Suite
- Windows, Linux, macOS
- HTML5/CSS web-hosting

## Insurance/Billing

- Medical coding
- Healthcare enrollment

#### Communication

- Multi-line phones
- Professional writing
- Friendly demeanor

#### Personal

- CPR certification
- Excellent health

# REFERENCES Shaoli Bhadra

Refugee Medical Program Coordinator YMCA International Services shaoli.bhadra@ymcahouston.org

office: 713-339-9015 ext. 1051

### Salimah Shamsuddin

Refugee Case Management Coordinator YMCA International Services salimah.shamsuddin@ymcahouston.org office: 713-339-9015 ext. 1019

### **Katie Devine**

Assistant Professor of Physics The College of Idaho kdevine@collegeofidaho.edu

office: 208-459-5064

#### Nick Puccio

Houston Director Texas Episcopal Service Corps npuccio@epicenter.org

office: 713-353-2107